<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: management | This Is My Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://kykim.github.com/blog/categories/management/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kykim.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-02T18:49:49-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://kykim.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kevin Y. Kim]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[kykim@kykim.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parable of the Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://kykim.github.com/blog/2012/07/23/parable-of-the-day/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-23T16:09:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kykim.github.com/blog/2012/07/23/parable-of-the-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Americans and the Japanese decided to engage in a boat race. Both
teams practiced hard and long to reach their peak performance levels.
On the big day they felt ready. The Japanese won by a mile. The
American team was discouraged by the loss. Morale sagged. Corporate
management decided that the reason for the crushing defeat had to be
found, so a consulting firm was hired to investigate the problem and
recommend corrective action.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The consultant's finding: The Japanese team had eight people rowing
and one person steering; the American team had one person rowing and
eight people steering. After a year of study and millions spent
analyzing the problem, the consultant firm concluded that too many
people were steering and not enough were rowing on the American
team. So as race day neared again the following year, the American
team's management structure was completely reorganized. The new
structure: four steering managers, three area steering managers, and a
new performance review system for the person rowing the boat to
provide work incentive.</p>

<p>The next year, the Japanese won by TWO miles!!!</p>

<p>Humiliated, the American corporation laid off the rower for poor
performance and gave the managers a bonus for discovering the problem.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
